<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Fayez Alshehri</title>
    <link>https://fayez-als.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Fayez Alshehri</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://fayez-als.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://fayez-als.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://fayez-als.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Coding Neural Networks for Logistic Regression Using Linear Algebra &amp; Numpy</title>
      <link>https://fayez-als.github.io/post/2021-07-13-coding-neural-networks-for-logistic-regression-using-linear-algebra-numpy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fayez-als.github.io/post/2021-07-13-coding-neural-networks-for-logistic-regression-using-linear-algebra-numpy/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionNeural network’s most basic unit is a neuron. The way neurons interact and work together is the main determinant of the limits of a neural network’s complexity and sophistication.Similar to neurons found in the human brain, once a neuron receives a signal it is capable of combining it through linear regression, transforming it, and producing a new signal that is then received by another neuron.
Neural networks are often seen in layers, with neurons in different levels interacting through the weighted attachments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blossom Marathon Analysis using R language</title>
      <link>https://fayez-als.github.io/post/2021-06-02-blossom-marathon-analysis-using-r-language/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fayez-als.github.io/post/2021-06-02-blossom-marathon-analysis-using-r-language/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionWith the massive explosion of data generated and published in the past few decades comes new challenges. Data analysts and scientists now have to discover patterns in this unprecedented amount of raw and often redundant data. In order to do that, data must go through a very critical and sensitive process of cleaning to produce high quality data that can later be used to estimate and draw generalizable conclusions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using React.js to make a Music Player</title>
      <link>https://fayez-als.github.io/post/2021-05-12-using-react-js-to-make-a-music-player/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fayez-als.github.io/post/2021-05-12-using-react-js-to-make-a-music-player/</guid>
      <description>introductionThis is a simple project that was completed in approximately 3 hours Source Code. The whole project was programmed using React Hooks/Material-U. I relied very heavily on my pre-existing programming knowledge since other online tutorials have made the simple tasks unnecessarily more difficult. Once I had a grasp of how to manipulate audio documents using React the whole project was practically done and the only decisions and work left to be done was related to the overall aesthetics and looks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello R Markdown</title>
      <link>https://fayez-als.github.io/post/2020-12-01-r-rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fayez-als.github.io/post/2020-12-01-r-rmarkdown/</guid>
      <description>R MarkdownThis is an R Markdown document. Markdown is a simple formatting syntax for authoring HTML, PDF, and MS Word documents. For more details on using R Markdown see http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com.
You can embed an R code chunk like this:
summary(cars)## speed dist ## Min. : 4.0 Min. : 2.00 ## 1st Qu.:12.0 1st Qu.: 26.00 ## Median :15.0 Median : 36.00 ## Mean :15.4 Mean : 42.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
